Okay, and we're planning
this retreat.  My heart and I, we were
thinking about what the classes would be like
, what classes needed
preparation, and it was an
unfortunate thing in Buddhism that we wouldn't be able to complete
the teaching class, like
the final part of the training which took
us 12 years, but we
completed it, and let's give
ourselves a round of applause.
And there's another important sermon
called Don Chin's.  Please
speak up.  Don
chin.  Don Chin means that the tendency
to think about the pen is coming from the main
pen itself.  And we cling
to the pen that was made
in the factory.  Do you understand what I mean
?  And when you hold onto it, you
believe that the milk coming is being produced
in a factory, and you have a
mental illness.  Okay.  It's
called a donin.  Okay.
It means that there is something between
two
people, it means causing trouble for
those two people.  And in America, there's something
special that sometimes you
can see, if you're visiting
a place, a
driver accidentally hits someone,
and then they get
very angry, and they get out of the car, and
they start acting like they're in Greece,
and they get out of the car, and luckily, the other person shows
them a gun, and okay, it's fine.
And it's like you meet someone who
speaks
Tibetan.  And in one book, there's
a long book of
poems called the battles
between the good part of
your mind and the bad part
of your mind.  And it was a bit of a
fight.  And my teacher introduced
me to it many years ago, maybe 35
to 40 years
ago.  He taught me, and he taught
me for a very long time, and
he couldn't finish it because
he died before he could
complete it.  And I think it was bad
luck not to complete it.
So I think I have to teach, I
like teaching it and I will teach, I will need to
finish the translation part
and then I will
feel like I have finished it and
it is finished and it is a
battle within a battle in
your mind, it's like in
your mind it is divided into two, a
good part and a bad part.  And you know,
angels and demons are fighting
each other inside you, and it's
amazing.  It's a
great conversation and it's the kind of conversation
we have all the time and you know, this
guy, this person,
you know, this person hurt
me and I know, but I know,
but I know about the pen story,
but this guy, this guy,
this guy is different, he's not like the
other guy, okay? And we talk about it
hundreds of times a day, and I really do
it hundreds of times a day, and I
sit in my house.
And when the best thing
you can do is open up to your lama
and put the teacher in Kyoto and
all the toilets are warm
and we have electricity and I think it's
like heaven.
But when I got back to the
diamond mountain and or my house and
I didn't think I could sit
down on that toilet but when I
sat
down and even though whatever it was,
I was arguing with
my own mind and my mind
was arguing with my own mind and
it was beautiful.  It's a great book,
and okay, team, do you remember?
I don't know.  We started
14 years ago.  It was 14 years ago, and I'm
still working on it,
but I don't have much time to teach
it anymore.  But I refused to give up,
and that's because I'm stubborn.  Okay, is that alright?  I am
following if you are following the
Diamond Vehicle, if you are
a Diamond Vehicle person
and perhaps the Buddha sent
this book to you this time, perhaps
you cannot speak, and of
course.  Certainly, you
can't say, "Oh no, no, that
your path to the Diamond Sutra is with this book.
Maybe this book will help you
on your path to the Diamond Sutra,
and I will take it, I will take it, and I...
but I haven't finished it yet,
but I will take it, and maybe
I will finish
it, but it hasn't... it has
never been translated correctly."
And okay.  And I want everyone in the
world to use
it.  And when I teach, I can understand
it better, and by teaching it,
by explaining anything to
anyone.  That means you will learn it as if you were a
teacher.  You are all teachers
now.  When you want to learn it in the
best way possible.  Okay.  And you should try to use that
for your sister or your son
.  Okay.  How old is your son?  Oh, you're 18
already?  Hey, I'm 19 years old
now.  Okay, he'll be a lecturer who
goes astray
next year.  And I think the Buddha has
already sent this book to you, and you
should finish it with me, okay?
And so we're going to make it
part of the surplus diamonds.  And of course,
that's the main part of the
debate about the meaning of "believe it or not."  And it
's a very
unique book, because it's fun and because it's
written in a fun way, okay?  And
I expect you to laugh, and
sometimes just laugh, and laugh out loud.
And even though you don't understand,
you still have to keep laughing, and
it's very, very funny, and it's the
truth.  Okay.  This part of his mind—
this is a part of my grandfather's mind—
before he sat down in
that special chair.  Okay.  And whoever complained,
okay.  And speaking of the weather, you know
.  Who made the weather cold
this morning and who didn't
make it cold this morning? Okay,
but it's colder than yesterday,
and that doesn't make sense.  Okay.
No, I mean, you guys are
complaining, and in your own minds,
and I call it the devil, okay, it's the
devil, the devil,
and the team and I have worked very
hard on this document because
you've heard about the idea of ​​the five
houses and all that's going on
with ACI,
and I think it's one of the
oldest organizations we have. It
started 10, uh,
two, it started 32 years ago,
and it has grown, it has grown, it
has grown, and YSI came in, and YSI appeared,
and DCI appeared, and SCM appeared,
and SSD
DLPP appeared, everything, everything, every
organization appeared because of ACI, which started 40
years ago, and it's growing
very big, and it has 18 foundational courses,
18 foundational courses,
and you guys, and it needs to be
completed within 6 or 7 years, those 18 courses,
and then you can
go.  Entering the Diamond Vehicle takes
about 14 years in total, and you need to do
all the meditation exercises
for another 5 years, making it
19 years in total.   Okay
.  And you can expect to be taking the
third introductory course.  But this is
becoming too much, and so what's
happening is okay.  What's happening
is that we want you all to become
teachers, and
we really want you to become
teachers.  And if you're really
stubborn and you want to cook
for yourselves, for your own sake, in
this desert, in this class, then
maybe you could become a
teacher.  Because becoming a teacher
is similar to cooking for
yourself, cooking for yourself
at the Diamond Mountain.  And saying it out loud causes a
lot of trouble.  And I think that
everyone who comes, especially to
this Kim Can Thua street, you are all
wonderful teachers.  And that's
my dream, guys.  That's
my dream.  That's what I've been doing these past few
years.
And there is a lot to be done.  You ca
n't study for 40 years and
become
teachers.  And my idea is that you
can specialize.  You guys are like
when you go to university;
you don't need to be like
a Bachelor of Science graduate.  Okay, either a
bachelor's degree in English or a bachelor's degree in
literature.  and you all
.  And our idea is that you
can start by calling
it differentiation, you can
differentiate, but you can also look
into your own heart
so that you can
fundamentally specialize in these five choices
.  Okay.  You can earn a
bachelor's or a doctorate and start teaching at
one of these five houses, and
it's like a
head house at Princeton University.  You
have to join a house and
you have to be loyal to your house
and you will have support and
you will have friends and you will
study together and you will
graduate together in your own
house and so we
want to do five years of house and the
choice is and the first thing is the
first rule as a teacher
is you can't remember and when
you can't remember something, ask the
audience, okay audience, what is it,
okay? The first thing is
a tradition about ACI, the
AC path you can take all the
traditional classes, you can
take six courses and then you can
take 18 more courses, a total
of 36 courses.  And you can learn
a basic technique.
And if you pass the 18
basic courses of ACI,
you will have learned all the
important things in
G science, and you don't need to sit there for 12
hours every day studying.
You do
n't really go into class and talk and do
nothing. You don't need to
have class today. You don't
need to talk to me.   Okay
.  You don't have to study like the
students in these Western schools
.  Okay.  It's absolutely insane.
These systems are absolutely
insane.  Okay.  You need to complete
the philosophy courses
.  And one of us, one of us is
okay.  And they want to
learn these philosophies and I'm the same, I
enjoy these philosophies and
I like talking about them and I and when it's like
learning these principles, if
you have attained Buddhahood
you will become a
philosopher, the philosophical path means
some people who like the Sumati house
say it's about meditation and some people
really like meditation and
you can this book or study
this book and this and there is
another book and the last 35 books are
not enough.  And you guys read
this book and you're like, 'Okay, can I
meditate for a bit?'  Okay, I
don't want to read books all
day.  And some people prefer
meditation, and some prefer to delve deeper
into it and truly enjoy it.  And
their dream was to become a
meditation teacher, and
not a Tibetan language teacher
.  Okay, do you understand?  But
it's okay.  You will have
qualifications, just like you will have
houses.  And
you will have the privilege and the
pleasure of joining
these meditation centers.  And we call them
Subi houses.   Okay
.  And by the way, what would you call truly
great meditators, truly great practitioners of meditation
?  There are some people with
very low backgrounds.  They don't
brag like Trendy does; that
meditation is the best kind of meditation
.  Okay, guys.  But he
didn't have a teacher and didn't look
like a doctor.  Okay, is that alright
?  Okay.  I mean, it's something
more understated, and you don't look
like a big, powerful businesswoman
.  Okay.  You are not like
those people involved in import and
export, those people who are the owners of
businesses in Vietnam.  Okay.  It's something like
that.  Okay.  By doing so, one can attain a
great meditative state without anyone knowing.   Okay
.  And if you have that attraction
to meditation and when you
see your future, when
you close your eyes and think about the
future where you are teaching meditation to a
group of people, then you are welcome to
join this Subati family.  What I mean
is that you don't just hear about
philosophy classes, but it
means you can specialize in
it.  Okay.  When I decide
who I am?
What I tell people
on the plane is, when you sit down, you see
someone you don't know, and
you say, "Okay, what are you doing?"
What is your profession?  And if
you're the one who's going to say, "I
'm your meditation teacher,
should I join? Is that okay?"  And
you are that person, and
okay, the house, the classic house.  Okay.  The
third house
is okay.  We call it the
mountain house, right?  Mountain house.  Okay.  Okay?
I was truly drawn to the retreat, the
tranquil retreat.  There are people who
are yearning for more opportunities to do
quiet, contemplative retreats
.  And if you have a new book, and
if I teach you
a new meditation exercise, then I'm really
sorry.  I'm very busy and I'm
sitting in my cabin.  I can't
read books, I can't be
like Ok.  They are in a
deep, quiet retreat, and they want
people to see them every six months.  It's
similar to Lamap.  And if
you are such a person,
their dream is to become one of the
great people who have been in
many retreats, and you can
join these homes.  I do
n't know, I'm not sure what
percentage of people would want to
join whichever house they prefer.  But
I truly believe
that if you can have
about five houses in one of the
starting houses when you begin, then I
think that's enough.  I don't care,
I'm not interested.  It's just that there are
100 people.  Okay.  And okay.  If there were only
two people, just two people,
in this retreat house, I
wouldn't really care.  I'd like
you guys to be there, is that okay?  Okay.  And
what is the fourth house?  Okay.  Terraced house
.  Terraced house.  The tree cart.   Okay
.  Everyone calls it Lam.
Anyway, everyone calls it Lam Dream.
When you look back over the last 12 years,
it's been a huge topic and
we've included it in
this lengthy lamin.  And I had
John Brandy's database
.  You can solve the remaining part; the
rest of your lives
will be very, very beautiful, and
we completed it within 12
years.  And if you really did it,
it took 12
years, and it took another 12 years, 24 years,
and the deadline became a master of
Dream building,
and everyone I know
wants to be in the fifth house,
it's the diamond house.  Okay,
right?
Because everyone wants to live in the
house of excess diamonds, I will, but
I will not allow you to live in
the house of excess diamonds because you
will squander all the other houses.  Okay.
And I had a plan, and
one of the four houses you
don't need to decide today,
you don't need to cut your blood to
sign the contract, just think about it, and
it's when you attract the trap,
and I'm going to tell you something very
profound, and
my teacher gave me advice,
and isn't one of these things you
really hate, right?  I'm right
.  That's the ACI class, ACI cohort 13.
Why do I think so? Because it's an
unlucky number.  But I... but...
because I hate logic.  Okay, sure.
And the teacher's advice was to
join the house you don't like.
Join a group you don't like
because you're not good
at it, and then you can balance
your life.  When you become
proficient in something you don't
enjoy, you become a
master of both.  And
do you understand what I mean then?  You are already
good at meditating.  You need to
study Reit.org and/or
philosophical theories.  Okay, is that alright?  But that
's just one option.  I'm
not forcing you.  You
can always dream and think about being
in a cabin and avoiding
everyone else and you can
join a resort house, a
mountain house or whatever makes you
comfortable.  Feel free to relax, and what
we're asking of you
this week is that you
pretend to choose one of those houses.
Okay, but try to find out
how you feel.  But
I will tell you the story of
my wife, and I will never
repeat what she did.  And I took my wife
to buy underwear in
Cottonwood.
And inside the shop, there were no
chairs for people to sit while waiting, so I had to
stand.  Okay.  And she tried on 42 pairs of
underwear, and how many pairs of underwear
did she buy?  There aren't any.   Okay
.  And because you have to try
different houses to see
which one suits you best.
I won't have an Apple.  You have to choose
one or the other.  Okay, sure.
But let's see which one suits
you best.  And the great thing I
did on the
tour with Stanley
was that I was very, very
brave and I bought my wife a pair of
jeans and they fit her perfectly. And
if you were to write about my life
after I die,
it should start with how I
bought my wife those jeans
and they fit her perfectly,
like in Harry
Potter.  How do they
decide which house they live in?
How do they decide what you
call it?  What is it called?
What is that hat called?
What is a hat?
Oh, it's a hat! We can't
have a wizard's hat, but in
the Harry Potter stories, you
get to have one.   Okay
.  But anyway,
we don't have this hat for you.
You have to make the decision for
yourselves.   Okay
.  Oh,
what is Harry Potter's house?
Anyway
.  Okay.  The game this week is... and
if you guys are busy, I
know too.  Whenever you add more information,
you should choose a house that
you would like to live in.  What does that mean?
Why do you want to become a
teacher?  This is what I mean.  What do you
like to teach others in a
primary way, and you can practice,
you will focus on it, and we will
help you focus on whatever
you choose to become a
PhD. We will
help you focus on that, and we will
design specialized courses
for you, but that doesn't
mean everyone else can't
come. We design
specialized courses to make you
teachers
of your own house, and
you need to complete all the
requirements in your house to be
allowed to join the Diamond House, okay?
There are four
paths to the fifth house because
everyone wants to go straight to the
fifth house, okay? But we will ask
you to go around and around, and
we ask you to choose one of
those four houses, and only then can you
enter the Diamond House,
okay? And the Diamond House is a
super house.  There are houses for everyone to live
in, those four houses are really doing
very well, and when you can
become teachers, and one of
these things, and thinking about what you
can become as
a teacher, is to visualize yourself,
imagine yourself as a
teacher, and that is the Vajrayana path,
and that is one of the
most important teachings of
Vajrayana, is to visualize how you will teach, how
you will, and when you
become teachers, and that is one
of the most
important Vajrayana meditations, and most importantly,
what you will look like.  Okay.
I look like I have four
arms like a
lion, and four legs like a lion's staff
.  And one of the practical exercises
of Diamond on the Golden Path
often involves visualizing
yourselves.  What kind of people will you become,
and sometimes you
can do that, and we'll talk about
it.  Okay, sure.  And now the
fun part is we're going to have, let's just call it, the
book, and angels and
demons.  The book of angels and demons.
And the fun part is that
you guys have to help me, you have to
help me create a document, a
flowchart for that document.
It's like I took the book that you guys took,
I took the book that's like the
last class that I gave us,
that Gibson book in my book,
and I cut out the first page,
and I put this picture
here, and I taught it from
this picture.  Okay, and I taught it using
this picture.  And what I do for the
angel and the devil is that I don't have
these images.  And why?  Because you yourselves are the ones who have to
create
these photos.  And each house
will have images for
teaching a part of the book
on your journey.  And I will
teach, and what I will teach today is
a few verses of angels and
demons.  Okay.  That bad person, that
bad person.  Those bad people are very,
very rude.  And when it comes to me, I
like each house and the team
will take you through them.  And
we sat together and we
and you will design
these images and you will design
images to teach it.  And we're
going to have a very special class.  And
we're going to proceed to cut these four
parts.  And each house will stand up
to present these things.  And that
's all we're going to
teach you about the first tiger letter from
your house.  Okay.
We and you need to do it, and you will do
it.  Okay.  I used a contract
with
an image service and I bought a lot of
images from them
for many years and I had to search
online and
I but there were some
really stupid images,
but it's getting
better and better and now you
can design images
and you can write a
sentence and the
AI ​​will create the
image for you.  Okay.  And maybe they
have five fingers, just five
fingers.  Okay.  And I really like it and I
actually use it a lot.
And maybe in the future you
can use videos from
your AI, but using it
in my generation is quite
cool, and you can
use AI to create
images, and it's a great teaching tool, and it
will make the
audience more interested and you can
make them enjoy it
more.  Okay.  And you can test, you
can check what your students have done
.  Okay.  What is the meaning of
this picture, and what is its significance
?  And this picture should have a little bit of
fuel, this, and it's a very
powerful way of teaching
visually to tell
stories, and it will be easier to remember the
philosophies from the images,
right?  And they and it will tell the story
through the images, and
I
want, okay, I want four images from each
theme, and that I can teach you, I
will give them to
you, and I and the team will decide,
okay, who has the best picture, okay, who
gets the
golden hat, but in the end, we will have
the idea, we will have the enjoyment of it,
have fun with it.  Okay.  Okay.  There was a
man from
Mexico.  We've been doing this for a
long time.  Do you remember
?
How many years has it been?  Ten years
ago?
He did his best
and it was
fantastic.  I was
just kidding.  Okay, he's returning from Kyoto.  Okay,
Hoa Hoa and Adam.
They had some really
great classes in Kyoto, Japan.
He and Adam had some really
great classes and there was a team event and Nick
went there
too and it was a lot of fun for
them, but coincidentally the
plane landed in Hawaii.
I lived in Hawaii for about six
months.
Right?  I... I... I don't know.
But if you want something like this, you
can fill out an application to get a learning
package, and they went to Kyoto and
helped many people. They led the
course, and everyone
can do it. It's called Jbox, and the
project is called Gbox.  Okay, I'll talk
about this project.
And Adam did, but the angels
and
demons... think about what kind of pictures
you could create with whom
.  And it will help you teach
better, and it will help all the students
remember the lessons better, remember the lectures
more clearly.
And in
my opinion
, anyone in this classroom
and anyone who studies online
can become a teacher.  Okay,
it's your responsibility to teach
these things to everyone else.  Everyone is
different.  Okay.  Since Adam isn't here, I
'll tell you this instead.  Okay.
Adam's first class was 12 years
ago, in
Phoenix.  I trained him on
how to speak, and he stood
up and looked like this
.  I'm like this, you see.  And I said
Adam, Adam, I called
Adam, and Adam, and Adam, sit down, and Adam
sat down.  Okay, we're working on
that.  And he froze completely.
Okay, but I'm also completely
frozen about my first day of teaching
.  Okay, you will study.  Okay, you
can study.  You will learn from my opinion that
everyone can, everyone
should become a
teacher.
And within that Mahayana tradition,
you are not allowed to learn it unless
you intend to teach it within
that ancient tradition.  You're
not allowed to take that class if you
don't intend to teach
it
.  And sometimes nobody says '
listen,' and I say, 'Are you listening
?'   '
s okay the bad part of your mind and he
says you should lead people by the hand
to the nothing at
all teach them not to think about
anything make them
Ok.  Sit
down and cross your legs.  Don't think about anything at
all.  Who's saying that?  I hope
those guys are okay?
[Music]
This is a meditation system and
you might laugh, but you know, back in the
day,
when I first met
my first yoga teacher,
David Sharon, I didn't
know that I
could learn yoga.
And when you go to the
hotel and see the
first yoga class, you know, like
every family you come to, and
the great story in Hong
Kong about the Chinese language,
and the women,
like,
I go in there,
and the women are like, they're so tense
like
this.  So,
let me tell you,
yoga classes are something
I've attended in
many countries, and in each country
I've been to, I've heard
about many different kinds of
meditation, some really intense ones.
She lets your mind wander
freely, and that's okay.
Then suddenly I realized
how bad something was
and I was very shocked and I rarely attend
someone else's meditation lecture
and
nganuki saw the person who
personally fought against
his request
and in 400 years there was
a problem
when people taught like that and
in this book it's
like the devil,
okay?  That's an important thing, is
n't it?
When you create a picture like
that, it's not a bad yoga class
or anything like that.  And generally,
yoga is good, and asanas are also good.  And there's
meditation, but meditating
before those yoga poses
is ridiculous.
[Music]
And I'm like, like when you
get on a plane and they give you something like a
hand guard, right?  That means
when they teach meditation, I
cover my hands, and when they start practicing the
postures, I open them up.  You can
go to classes like that and you
can learn, but it's an outdated concept
where people think
meditation is about not thinking about anything at
all.
Now listen, in the
context of the Vajrayana tradition
, the goal of the Vajrayana
is to essentially complete
your work before you die.  And
if you don't think that way, then it's
as
if
we don't know who will die first and who will die later.
And so it's as if I could
still be sitting here, but there's no
one else around,
and I don't know who's still here and
who's
gone.  So, in the
diamond system,
you should basically try to achieve your goal
before you die.  And that's a
thing, you always have a
background,
you can think you're going to have a
car accident
tomorrow, and
when you know someone, you think you're going to have a car accident,
and all of that is the
race in the regular diamond.
I think of it as when you sneak into the
excess diamond, the goal of the excess diamond,
the reason for the excess diamond, one of the
most important ideas of the
excess diamond is to complete it and
then
relax.  And then, if you die, it's just a matter of life and death
.
My death is different from the end of
your death.  I know that.
I knew it was
happening, and I knew it was going to happen,
I knew it was going to happen
five minutes ago.  Those are the things the
teachers see as waiting for
me, and they see it as your responsibility
.  You have to take care of
that, and that's what
surplus diamonds are.  That emphasis, that portraying
a lifetime as a person who teaches
you about meditation and
nothingness, is literally
killing you.  It's like a joke
.  It's not just a waste of
your 10 minutes before studying;
it's a waste of your whole life.
Your irreplaceable lifespan.  I essentially sold the
company to Warren
Buffett.  The person who supposedly went from
81 billion to 143 billion in
that company.
And if you have
100.43 billion dollars, then he should
consider it as buying something for a few hours, like someone else
.  Okay.  Let's say I'll buy it, consider it
a day's worth of your time,
but he can't actually do
that.  Right.  No one can do
that.  The person who teaches
you what they consider to be terrible meditation
is actually killing you.  They are stealing
your time and making false accusations.  That's something that's
considered extremely bad.  It was a
tragedy; it was worse than
just having diarrhea
.  I'm quite envious that you
consider it like 10 pounds of octopus or 80 bags of octopus
.
And it's not a small thing; it's
not just wasting 10 minutes of your time
before the listening class, but they're taking away
time that no one
can ever give back to you.  Teaching meditation
incorrectly is like
cutting off someone's hand.  It
's a very serious matter.
It's an interesting debate, but
it's not an interesting debate
because this person
is truly
evil because they're teaching meditation
incorrectly, a
terrible tragedy
.  It's kind of like treating someone as if they
died in a car accident
.  It was terrible.  Someone would consider it a
waste of their time.
This is the devil's boast about
how fast this system is going to move.  The
result of this meditation is that
you won't find it in
this life or the
next.
Or, you can meditate for just
one month and
achieve Buddhahood. All of you will
achieve liberation.
Who's saying that? That's the devil, right?
Listen! The Vajrayana is
the fastest way, but it takes a
lot of time, okay?
If someone were to promise you
instant liberation, I'd like to tell you
this story.  There was someone
sitting next to me, someone sitting next to me, it
felt like being on an airplane.
This is like asking if you want to know the secret
about the stock market.
You have to invest in
Nvidia. Nvidia has a
new chip, a very
high-tech, cutting-edge chip. And
what's the name of the chairman of Sony?
[Music]
Mr.
Monita.  This is what is considered,
and this is a famous book
.  What was the name of that book?  That's
essentially a product
made in Japan.  And I love
him so much that I'm telling you, he said, "Let
me tell you this."  If
someone actually knew
which stock was going to go up tomorrow, do
you think they would tell
you
?  YES.  And that's something that ca
n't be denied, right?
If someone knew for sure
which stock was going to go up
tomorrow, they'd have to tell
you, right?
It's like they just put their money
in there and consider it as them making money.
And I laughed and said
that I didn't participate in the
stock market at all.  I didn't, and I
suppose even the founder of
Sony Corporation would say that I didn't buy any
shares. Why?  Because it's just
gambling.  It's similar to
watching a horse race.  You
could say all the experts in the world
know different things,
but if they know and consider
themselves experts, they will
make money quietly.  What do I mean
?  That, that, that thing that
this person is promising, that is a
feasible promise.  Look, look at my cloak!
The point of this is that it
proves I am a master of
chanting, and with those crazy people coming,
it's as if I'm having sexual relations
with all the other students.
All of that is just
like the stock market.  Go ahead, go ahead, go ahead
.  And what about me? Would that be
okay if I went to study?  You understand what
I mean, right?
The hat doesn't make a
monk, does it?
I also have those
unfounded promises that
claim you can
achieve enlightenment
instantly; they only delay
your enlightenment.  You need to
work hard in a fixed way and
sit on a meditation cushion, sit
in that rit cabin for many bad days,
right?  And then, let's assume you'll achieve
your goal, okay?
Diamonds are not something to be treated
like a piece of candy; they represent the fruits of
labor.  And I like the next stanza.  To call someone an
extremely stupid person is to be
unable to tie their own thick rope.  Who
said that?  That's a
devilish name, isn't it?  And it
seems he is accusing
the beautiful angel called
intelligence.  Regarding the understanding of the
lady's pen, it's
not considered a name that's considered
very
stupid, and it's as if
he said that
he has the ability to do
great things, but
here he can only do
small things with
real intelligence,
and in English, he ca
n't even tie a
thick rope.  It means it's incredibly
stupid.  "Dương nguc" means a
stupid head
.  YES.  And it's as if he's
accusing this angel of wisdom
.  Who's speaking?  That's another evil spirit,
you know.  He accused her of being a friend who
only appears once and
then simply disappears.  He said
that you are very beautiful,
very wise, you understand the story of
the pen, you live by the story of the
pen, right?  So why is it that
you never feel like you're
at home, that you spend all
day somewhere, that you're just running around
somewhere?  Why can't I ever
feel like I'm going
home?  You are so beautiful, you are so compassionate, you are
so wise.  Why are you never
home?  Why?  What does he mean?
This means that actually understanding the
story of the pen is something that happens only
once a month, like two
minutes for example, and he's accusing
her in that way.  And then there's the
terrible wife, the wife is
considered
right, and the evil demon is considered to have
accused her, just like this god of wisdom
.  Who was she with?
Who was that guy, and what was his name
?  What does that mean?
This means that people think about the
story of the pen as if it only happens once
a week, and for the rest of the week, they consider it
complaining about other people.  I can't
believe there's such a terrible person
.  It only happens about once a
month, and you think, "Oh,
that's coming from
me."  That means she's
not home very often.
That's what it means.  Do you understand?
So he's accusing her of
essentially
deceiving her husband.  And
who is this husband?  That is
ignorance.  And can they live together
?  And she's
practically not home very often.
And let's say you need to
visualize that image in
your mind, okay?
How much time do we have left?
And those who
hope to accumulate
good karma, surpassing
any measure,
should now come and serve at
my feet—whoever is speaking here,
we can call this
the two-
minute Buddha.  If they practice
meditation in the void,
they can attain
Buddhahood in a few
days.  If you truly want to
create good karma, then
you should serve the devil—incidentally,
there are devils in Buddhism—and
in
Buddhism, the devil is
asking you to think
about the story of the pen; it comes from
its own side, that's
its job. The person who
insulted you yesterday didn't
come from you.  That's his job,
and he's trying to make
you believe that the person who
hurt you is actually
him, and that
you'll continue to
blame everyone for the rest of your life.
She should probably consider herself jealous of me
because she thinks I'm powerful, very
powerful.  Who's speaking?  Those are
essentially the boastful words of the
devil.  Is that correct?  It's
not true that she's considered
weak, that she's considered
absent, that she's never home.
Because if you think about where,
like the pen itself, you
'll be more patient with others.  And if
you can't remember, then you
're weak.
YES.  She's stronger, but that's only if
she's not home.
If she never visited
home, she would never have the
opportunity to demonstrate her strength
.  When you study
these ancient wisdoms with Michael,
you need to learn this.  When you're
sleepy, you should do
this.  That's exactly the third skill level, is
n't it?  And this is level two
.  Sleep with your eyes open.
And
the "but" now is that you'll need to be completely
exhausted to
fight me.  Why would
you consider yourself not going home?  It's
only a problem when
you're at home.  You become suspicious
when you see that person acting as if they're coming from somewhere near
you or not.  Why do
you consider yourself not to be living at home?  Because it's as if
you've decided that person
hurt you.  The person who hurt
you should consider the hurt to be coming from their side.
And that's a
bad person.  And you have to keep trying to
remember
those things.  Consider that person as someone who has
hurt me.  It's as if he said
that, as if he was speaking from
me, but it's also as if he
hurt me.
This is the best way to pretend to
forget about Buddhism when someone
hurts you and calls you a
scoundrel.  So, would it be
easier to
have a
mental struggle like, "Maybe
he's from me, but
he's almost as ugly as that?"
YES.  Those were the last words of what
seemed like a
wicked devil.  Now, it's as if
our spiritual body will
reappear.  It
means the wise lady is
back, I'm home, my love.
What does that mean?  It means she understands
the story behind the pen and uses it in
real life.  There are some people
who understand the story of the pen but
never use it in real life
and instead always complain about
others.  Now it seems she'll be
responding to that devil again
.  When I was sitting inside, it felt like
a G-level course, or like a
refugee camp.
With a temperature of 120
degrees, which is about 45°C, and it was raining so heavily that
everyone around
me was practically covered in leprosy, I made
a promise that
when I became a teacher
in the future, I would make
my students suffer, and that promise
has now come true.
He's not someone who sleeps at night, is he
?  And consider it
an illusion, even if your meditation
is just too good.  You are a master of
meditation because you sit there and pretend not to
think about anything at all.  But it's not just that
you lack
those good qualities, you also lack the
tools to acquire
them.  This means that in
this case, if you don't know how to
meditate and no one teaches you
how to meditate in a way that makes you feel like you're
meditating and not thinking about anything at
all, then you can never be
a good person because you
lack the tools, the
skills, and
the kind of meditation where you just
sit and pretend not to think about anything.
Isn't that interesting?
Okay, we'll stop here.